So let's take a look at what products we have.
어떤 상품이 있나 한번 보죠
So, let's look at what reviews we have for different product names.
각 상품명에 어떤 리뷰가 있는지 봅시다
And here, we're gonna use the canvas again,
다시 Canvas로
to do a little bit of visualization.
시각화를 할 겁니다
And so, as with before, I'm going to do graphlab.canvas, and
전과 같이 Graphlab Canvas의
we'll set the target to be my ipath to on notebook so
대상을 IPython 노트북으로 설정하면
it will show up right here on the ipath on notebook as we're building this.
만들면서 확인할 수 있습니다
Now we can take one of the columns of this s frame of the product.
상품 SFrame에서 열 하나에
So for example, let's take the name of the product,
예를 들어 상품명에
and we can just hit .show on it, and that's gonna show
.show를 입력하면
a histogram of the different names of the different products in this data set.
여러 상품의 히스토그램이 뜨게 됩니다
So, for example, right here.
바로 이렇게 말이죠
So we see that this particular product, Vulli Sophie something gets the most
이 상품을 자세히 보죠 Vulli Sophie이 리뷰를 785개나 받았는데
reviews, 785 reviews as compared to like simple wishes something,
리뷰 562개를 받은 Simple Wishes나
something, 562 reviews and you can see that the number of reviews go down.
다른 상품과 비교해도 가장 많은 리뷰를 받았죠
Fisher Price products 489, 450.
Fisher Price 상품은 489, 450개네요
This is different baby products here that we're analyzing and
분석 대상과는 다른 유아용품들인데
you'll see the histogram of the different reviews of different products,
다양한 상품들의 다양한 리뷰 히스토그램입니다
number of reviews, so let's visit that first Vulli Sophie.
처음 나오는 Vulli Sophie를 보도록 하죠
What is that?
이게 뭘까요?
So let me tell you a little bit more about that product.
상품에 대해 좀 설명드리죠
So let's explore the so
Vulli Sophie 알아보기
called Vulli Sophie and this is an extremely popular product,
엄청나게 인기 있는 상품입니다
so it's actually, I happen to have one right here.
사실 제가 하나 갖고 왔습니다
This is Vulli Sophie, the giraffe teether.
Vulli Sophie는 기린 치발기입니다
So it's a little plastic giraffe.
귀여운 플라스틱 기린이죠
It's the most gifted product for babies on Amazon.
아마존에서 아기 선물로 가장 인기있는 상품입니다
And it's a teether, which means like babies like to chew on it.
치발기란 아기가 물고 노는 장난감을 뜻하죠
So lots of reviews for this giraffe for babies to chew on,
이 기린 치발기에 대한 리뷰가 많이 있습니다
and it's made out of plastic and squeaks.
플라스틱제에 삑삑 소리가 나네요
[SOUND] So this is what we're gonna talk about a lot today,
오늘 이것에 대해 자세히 알아보기로 하죠
this little giraffe [SOUND].
이 귀여운 기린이요
Now, let's look at the reviews for this particular giraffe.
이 기린에 대한 리뷰를 살펴보죠
So, I'm gonna call it giraffe.
기린 리뷰란 이름을
Giraffe reviews.
붙이죠
And then we're going to take all of those products that I have,
모든 상품 리뷰 중에서
all those product reviews, and I am going to select,
선택할건데
this is another filter, I am going to select those rows where
필터를 적용해서 이름이 이 기린과
the product name is equal to the name of this particular giraffe.
같은 상품의 열만 골라낼 겁니다
So this is Vulli Sophie
Vulli Sophie
the Giraffe Teether.
기린 치발기입니다
This is the product that we've been talking about.
지금까지 논하던 상품이죠
So if we take a quick look here, if I ask for the length of this new thing,
잠시 둘러보면서 길이가 얼만지,
giraffe reviews, this table, you see there's 785 reviews for this plastic toy.
기린 리뷰를 이 표에서 찾으면 785개입니다
[NOISE] Little teether.
귀여운 치발기
So, 785 reviews, and let's look at the ratings.
리뷰 785개의 별점을 봅시다
So, I'm gonna take the giraffe_reviews, the ratings, just for
giraffe_reviews에서 별점만을
this particular product, and I'm gonna do a .show in it like we've been doing.
골라내 .show를 합니다
I wanna look at particular view called the categorical view.
카테고리 뷰를 볼 겁니다
Which is going to give me, categorical view.
그러면 카테고리 뷰가 나오게 되겠죠
It's gonna give me a, sort of a histogram of the different reviews and
리뷰의 히스토그램과 점수를
how many scores we got.
출력해 줍니다
So, if you take a look at this little histogram here,
여기 이 히스토그램을 살펴보면
you will see something kind of interesting.
흥미로운 사실을 확인할 수 있죠
People love this thing.
사람들이 이 장난감을 아주 좋아하네요
535 the reviews were five stars.
리뷰 535개가 5점을 줬습니다
This is a product 535 five star reviews.
이 상품은 5점을 535개나 받았습니다
Then the next most common is four stars, then three stars.
그다음으론 4개가 많고, 3개,
Then it jumps down to one star, and finally two stars.
1개로 내려갔다 다시 2개 순입니다
So a good, sizable amount of people really hated this product.
꽤 많은 사람이 이 상품을 싫어하지만
But most people loved it.
대부분은 아주 좋아했습니다
It would be fun to do a kind of sentiment analysis try
감성분석으로 부정적 리뷰와 긍정적 리뷰가
to understand where the really negative reviews or
어떤 내용인지
the really positive reviews what this review is talking about.
감성분석을 해봐도 재미있을 것 같습니다
Just like we discussed in the lectures in this module.
이 모듈 강의에서 설명드린대로 말이죠
To do that, we'll build a sentiment classifier.
이를 위해 감성 분류기를 만듭니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]